Let's move on to the business axis simplifying and
offering a standard to the teams with good technologies.
I'm okay, but this platform is
also there to support the business.
It will shape it according to a certain
number of dimensions that will be more or
less important depending on the organizations.
For example, if your project is to offer
a public platform for many clients, you won't
have the same requirements as if you are
building an internal platform for your developers.
However, there are common dimensions that can
be found in almost all platforms.
I have listed some of them.
Here we will see dimensions such as ease of use.
Indeed, the idea is to remove a kind of cognitive load.
Developers must be able to use this
platform and the pipelines with ease.
But also the platform must provide
a certain level of reliability.
That's what the organization expects.
It wants everything deployed via the platform.
Not to break this platform can have a cost dimension.
Everything deployed on the platform must
be controlled in terms of costs.
The platform will also be required to
guarantee a certain level of performance so
that all services respond quickly.
This platform will need to be able
to withstand attacks such as Denial of
Service or Distributed Denial of service. DDoS.